Welcome to our new Line Chain Academy course, Building Amid Agents with Line Graph.
欢迎来到我们的Line Chain学院新课程：使用Line Graph构建多智能体。
Chat is a familiar user interaction pattern for agents, where user request something of an agent,
聊天是智能体常见的一种用户交互模式，用户向智能体提出请求，
an agent can call various tools, and respond to the user with an output.
智能体可以调用各种工具，并向用户输出响应。
But there are a lot of tasks for which chat isn't quite appropriate.
但有很多任务并不适合用聊天模式。
As an example, many users don't want to actually tell an agent do something.
例如，许多用户并不想真正告诉智能体该做什么。
They want an agent to listen passively to certain events and respond to them automatically.
他们希望代理能被动监听特定事件，并自动响应。
Many times we don't want agents to only handle one request at a time.
很多时候，我们不希望代理一次只处理一个请求。
We may want agents to handle many events concurrently.
我们可能希望代理能同时处理多个事件。
Sometimes we want agents to do work in the background for us,
有时我们希望代理能在后台为我们工作，
and only notify us at specific points, like when the work has been done,
只在特定时刻通知我们，比如工作完成时，
when they need clarification on something, or when they want to notify us about something.
当他们需要澄清某事，或想通知我们某事时。
And finally, with chat, you typically want the agent to work quickly.
最后，对于聊天，你通常希望客服能快速处理。
But if agents are doing work in the background, it can take much longer.
但如果客服在后台工作，可能需要更长时间。
A user isn't waiting around. They're only notified by the agent when appropriate.
用户不用一直等着。客服只会在适当的时候通知他们。
So this collection of attributes is what we call ambient agents.
所以这些属性的集合，我们称之为“环境代理”。
Now in this course, we're going to build an ambient agent that can handle email,
在这门课中，我们将构建一个环境智能体，来处理邮件
which is a great example of the kind of task you may want agents like this to take on.
这类任务很适合让智能体来完成
It's going to build an agent that can effectively manage your email inbox.
它能有效地管理你的收件箱
It will ingest incoming emails and perform actions like draft responses or schedule meetings.
接收邮件，并执行起草回复或安排会议等操作
Now because these are sensitive tasks, we're going to show how to use human loop to approve certain agent actions.
由于这些任务比较敏感，我们将展示如何使用人工审核来批准某些智能体操作
And importantly, we're also going to introduce memory so that the agent learns from our feedback over time.
重要的是，我们还会引入记忆功能，让智能体能从我们的反馈中不断学习。
And by the end of this course, you're going to understand all these components
学完这门课，你就能理解所有这些组件
and how they can be used generally to build agents, not just that handle email,
以及它们如何被普遍用于构建智能体，不只是处理邮件的智能体，
but they can handle many different types of tasks.
还能处理许多不同类型的任务。
So how can we actually build this?
那么，我们到底该如何构建它呢？
Let's take the simplest possible email system.
让我们用最简单的邮件系统举例。
For every incoming email, the assistant produces a response email.
每收到一封邮件，助手就会生成一封回复邮件。
Now the assistant can send that response using tool calling,
助手可以通过调用工具发送回复，
which I'll talk about briefly in a minute.
我稍后会简单介绍。
And if you think about the system in terms of agency versus predictability,
如果你从“自主性”和“可预测性”的角度来思考这个系统，
where agency is the ability for the system to make different decisions and predictability is,
代理能力是指系统做出不同决策的能力，可预测性则是指
simply the predictability decisions the system makes,
系统做出决策的可预测性。
this would be low agency but high predictability.
这就是低代理能力，但高可预测性。
It will always call a tool to send off an email for every incoming email that it receives.
它会为收到的每封邮件调用工具发送邮件。
The central concept underpinning this system and agents more broadly is tool calling.
支撑这个系统乃至更广泛的代理的核心概念是工具调用。
Let's imagine we had an email API.
假设我们有一个邮件API。
This could be the Gmail API as an example.
比如Gmail API。
We can turn that into a tool and bind it to an LLM.
我们可以把它变成一个工具，然后绑定到一个大型语言模型（LLM）上。
When we do that binding process, the LLM understands the arguments necessary to actually call that tool.
在绑定过程中，LLM会理解调用这个工具所需的参数。
So when it receives a request,
所以当它收到请求时，
it reasons about the request and can make a decision to call the tool,
它会分析请求，然后决定是否调用工具，
but importantly produces a structured output,
但重要的是，它会生成一个结构化的输出，
which contains the arguments that the tool actually needs.
其中包含工具实际需要的参数。
Independently, then, the tool can be executed with those arguments in order to,
之后，工具就可以独立地用这些参数来执行，
in this case, send off an email.
在这个例子中，就是发送一封邮件。
Now it's important to note that a simple system to always call an email tool is pretty limited.
值得注意的是，一个简单的系统，如果总是调用邮件工具，会很受限。
What if we don't want to respond?
如果我们不想回复呢？
So there's many different ways people have found to effectively lay out workflows.
所以人们找到了许多有效的方法来规划工作流程。
This is just LLM calls within predefined code paths.
这只是预定义代码路径中的LLM调用。
That can instrument specific logic.
它可以实现特定的逻辑。
Here's an example where we're put a router prior to that send email tool call.
举个例子，我们在调用发送邮件工具前，
This router then makes decision about whether or not we're going to send the email.
先放了一个路由器，它会决定是否发送邮件。
If we make a decision to send, we'll then go ahead and proceed to what we just talked about,
如果决定发送，我们就会继续执行刚才说的，
an LLM with access to an email tool and the email sent.
让大语言模型访问邮件工具，然后发送邮件。
Now if you think about this system, we've bump up the agency a little bit.
思考一下这个系统，我们稍微提升了自主性。
Now it has the ability to make a decision.
现在它能做决定了。
It can decide whether or not to respond.
它能决定是否回应。
And in turn, it's a little bit less predictable.
反过来，它就没那么可预测了。
We don't quite know what I'll decide given it an incoming email.
我们不确定它收到邮件后会怎么决定。
Now let's push this even further.
现在，我们再进一步。
Imagine we took that LLM and instead of giving it a single tool right email,
想象一下，我们用这个大型语言模型，不是只给它一个工具，比如写邮件，
we give it a collection of different tools.
而是给它一系列不同的工具。
And every time it called a tool, we just returned the output of that tool call back to the LLM.
每次它调用一个工具，我们都把工具调用的输出返回给大型语言模型。
We'll let the LLM think about what was performed and decide what to do next.
我们让大型语言模型思考执行了什么，然后决定下一步做什么。
We let that proceed in a loop until some termination condition.
我们让这个过程循环进行，直到达到某个终止条件。
This very simply is an agent.
这很简单，就是一个智能体。
And as noted, the agency is quite a bit higher than the other two.
如前所述，它的自主性比另外两个高很多。
And one way to visualize that is with the initial system,
有个方法可以直观地理解，
for every incoming email, it made a single decision to write a response and send it.
最初的系统，每收到一封邮件，它就做一个决定：写回复并发送。
The agent in contrast can choose any sequence of tool calls given the tools it has access to.
而智能体则不同，它可以选择任何工具调用序列，只要它能访问这些工具。
So in this case, let's say it had access to three tools.
假设它能用三个工具。
Check calendar schedule meeting, write an email.
查看日历、安排会议、写邮件。
It can pick any sequence.
它可以根据邮件输入，
It wants based upon the email input.
选择任意顺序。
Now a very important question is how to think about workflows or his agents.
那么，如何思考工作流或代理呢？
Typically, a good statistic is if you can easily draw the control flow on a whiteboard
通常，一个好的统计数据是，你可以在白板上轻松绘制控制流
and it's very easy to numerate in advanced workflows appropriate,
而且很容易在高级工作流中进行枚举，
and often is lower latency and cost than an agent.
而且通常比代理的延迟和成本更低。
But if you actually need more flexible decision making,
但如果你确实需要更灵活的决策，
and you can't quite know until runtime,
而且在运行时之前无法确定，
or in this case, until you receive an email,
或者像这种情况，直到你收到邮件，
how you want to respond in terms of tool calls,
你想如何用工具调用来回应，
then an agent is more appropriate.
那么代理就更合适。
And it's okay to trade off greater reasoning for higher latency and potentially higher cost.
牺牲推理能力来换取更高的延迟和潜在成本是可以接受的。
Now, line graph comes in because it's a framework of low-level components
现在，Line Graph之所以出现，是因为它是一个由低级组件组成的框架，
that lets you flexibly build and combine workflows and agents.
让你灵活地构建和组合工作流及代理。
Line graph is composed of nodes and edges where nodes are just units of work.
线图由节点和边组成，节点就是工作单元。
There's Python functions or TypeScript code that you control explicitly.
它们是你可以明确控制的Python函数或TypeScript代码。
So you'll just write those functions as you'll see shortly.
所以你只需编写这些函数，稍后你就会看到。
And everything happens with the node you have complete control over.
一切都发生在节点上，你拥有完全的控制权。
Now, edges are just transitions between nodes,
边是节点之间的转换，
which are going to lay out in advance as you build your workflow arrangement.
你可以在构建工作流编排时提前布局。
This will dictate the control flow of the application.
这将决定应用程序的控制流。
Now, one benefit of line graph is that because it uses very low-level components,
线图的一个好处是，因为它使用非常底层的组件，
just simply nodes and edges, you can build many different workflows as well as agents very easily.
仅仅是节点和边，你可以非常容易地构建许多不同的工作流和代理。
It allows you to kind of move to where you want to sit along this curve.
它能让你沿着这条曲线
You can build systems that are strictly agents.
移动到你想坐的位置。
You can build workflows.
你可以构建纯粹的代理系统。
You can combine agents and workflows together.
你可以构建工作流。
Now, one of the things we built into line graph that we found to be very important,
你可以将代理和工作流结合起来。
in particular, as we'll see here, building an ambient agent,
尤其是，我们将会看到，构建一个环境智能体，
is a persistence layer that enables human and loop and long-term memory.
是一个持久层，它能让人类参与到循环中，并拥有长期记忆。
As we'll see, it's important in many cases that agents can pause in a way human feedback.
我们会看到，在许多情况下，智能体能暂停以获取人类反馈，这很重要。
And that's what the persistence layer affords this.
这就是持久层所能提供的。
Not only that, it also gives us long-term memory.
不仅如此，它还赋予我们长期记忆。
The central idea behind persistence is that you have check pointing.
持久化的核心思想是检查点。
So, as you'll see, when you lay out your graph as a set of nodes,
稍后你就会看到，当你把图表布置成一组节点时，
the check pointer will save the state of the application.
检查点会保存应用程序的状态。
And if we pause it, that state is available for us to resume from later.
如果我们暂停它，这个状态就可以供我们以后恢复。
Line graph also comes built with an interactive development environment,
线图还内置了交互式开发环境，
Line Graph Studio, which you're going to see extensively throughout this course.
Line Graph Studio，在本课程中你会大量看到它。
And it provides an easy on-roam to deployment.
它提供了一种简单的部署方式。
And you'll see that we can very easily go from code running in a notebook
你会看到，我们可以非常轻松地将笔记本中运行的代码
to a deployable application.
转换为可部署的应用程序。
Before I actually build in our agent,
在我实际构建我们的代理之前，
I want to make sure we understand the fundamentals of Line Graph very clearly
我想确保大家对“线图”的基础知识有清晰的理解，
and how it works with Langshin and Langsmith.
以及它如何与LangChain和LangSmith协同工作。
Here's a general schematic where you can see the three together.
这是三者结合的示意图。
Langshin provides many integrations that we'll be using, particularly chat models,
LangChain提供了许多我们将用到的集成，特别是聊天模型，
and some very useful methods for binding tools or structured outputs.
以及一些非常有用的方法，用于绑定工具或结构化输出。
Line Graph will be using for agent orchestration.
线性图将用于智能体编排。
Langsmith remusing for observability, like tracing, as well as evaluation.
Langsmith 用于可观测性，比如追踪和评估。
And as you'll see, these three all play really nicely together,
稍后你会看到，这三者配合得很好，
but this is how they're related.
它们就是这样关联的。
Now, chat models are the foundation of LLM applications.
现在，聊天模型是大型语言模型应用的基础。
They're typically accessed through a chat interface,
它们通常通过聊天界面访问，
which takes the list of messages input,
聊天界面接收消息列表作为输入，
the returns and messages output,
返回消息输出，
and Langshin's standard interface for chat models called init chat model,
以及LangChain用于聊天模型的标准接口，名为“init chat model”，
where you can just simply pass the name of your provider and model,
你只需传入提供商和模型的名称即可，
as well as any parameters that you want to use.
以及任何你想用的参数。
Now, Langshin has some universal methods
LangChain有一些通用方法
for accessing chat models.
用于访问聊天模型。
Invoke just passes a single input to the chat model and returns an output.
Invoke只是将单个输入传递给聊天模型并返回一个输出。
In this case, we can just pass a string and under the hood,
在这种情况下，我们只需传递一个字符串，在底层，
it's converted into a chat message and sent in for us.
它会被转换成聊天消息，然后发送给我们。
We can see we get a message out.
我们可以看到我们收到了一条消息。
Now, here's the message, and you can see it has this content,
这就是那条消息，你可以看到它有这些内容，
as well as response metadata.
还有响应元数据。
Now, tools, as mentioned previously,
之前提到过，工具
are utilities that can be called by chat models.
是聊天模型可以调用的实用程序。
We can very easily create tools in Langshin
我们可以用LangChain轻松创建工具
from Python functions as an example using this tool decorator.
比如用Python函数，使用这个工具装饰器。
Now, this function is a tool,
现在，这个函数是一个工具，
and when we do this, the tool arguments, as well as description,
当我们这样做时，工具参数以及描述，
are automatically inferred.
自动推断。
These are things that are going to be passed to the model,
这些参数会传递给模型，
so the model knows what this particular tool is expecting.
让模型知道这个工具需要什么。
Now, one thing that's very nice is that
另外，LangChain 的
the chat model interface in Langshin
聊天模型接口
provides some common methods for working with tools.
提供了一些使用工具的常用方法。
In particular, this bind tools method,
特别是这个绑定工具的方法，
we can simply pass a list of tools in some useful parameters.
我们只需传入一个工具列表和一些有用的参数。
So this tool choice parameter means that the model is enforced
所以这个“工具选择”参数意味着模型被强制要求
to call any available tool that it has.
调用它拥有的任何可用工具。
So it will always have to call a tool.
所以它总得调用工具。
Parallel tool calls simply enforces the model calls a single tool at a time.
并行工具调用只是强制模型一次调用一个工具。
Sometimes models can actually make multiple tool calls at once,
有时模型可以一次调用多个工具，
and we can control that.
我们可以控制它。
So we define our model with tools.
所以我们用工具定义模型。
We invoke it just like before.
我们像之前一样调用它。
In this case, we invoke it with a message that's related to the tool it has,
在这种情况下，我们用一条与它拥有的工具相关的消息来调用它，
and we can see the tool call itself has the arguments needed
我们可以看到工具调用本身具有所需的参数
to actually run the tool to subject content.
来实际运行该工具以提交内容。
We can pass those args directly to our tool right email and just run it,
我们可以将这些参数直接传递给我们的工具，然后运行它，
and then we can see our tool was executed.
这样就能看到工具已执行。
So this is a very important concept to understand.
这是个非常重要的概念。
You can bind tools to LLMs.
你可以将工具绑定到大模型。
LLMs can call tools.
大模型可以调用工具。
Calling tools simply means that LLMs produce a structured output of arguments
调用工具，就是大模型会生成结构化的参数输出。
necessary to actually run the tool,
必须实际运行这个工具，
and then the tool can be independently run.
然后这个工具就可以独立运行。
This is really the foundational component for building agents.
这确实是构建智能体的基础组件。
And what we see above illustrates this simple flow that we saw before.
我们在上面看到的，说明了我们之前看到的这个简单流程。
We bind a single send email tool to an LLMs,
我们将一个发送邮件工具绑定到大语言模型上，
and enforce it to call that tool when responding to incoming emails or requests.
并强制它在回复邮件或请求时，调用该工具。
Now as discussed, workflows and agents really extend from this.
正如之前讨论的，工作流和代理都由此延伸。
In case of workflows, we can embed LLMs calls in predefined code paths.
对于工作流，我们可以在预定义的代码路径中嵌入大型语言模型调用。
As we see here, with a router prior to our LLMs calls our email tool.
正如我们所见，在大型语言模型调用我们的邮件工具之前，有一个路由器。
Agents just extend this a bit further,
代理只是在此基础上更进一步，
allowing LLMs to sequentially call tools in a loop.
让大型语言模型能循环、按序调用工具。
Now, land graph sits underneath any workflow or agent,
现在，LandGraph 成为所有工作流和代理的基础，
and it provides a few specific benefits we're going to walk through now in code in some simple examples.
它提供了一些特定的优势，我们现在将通过代码和一些简单示例来演示。
The first benefit is control.
第一个优势是控制。
It makes it very easy to define or combine ages and workflows.
它让定义或组合代理和工作流变得非常容易。
The second benefit is persistence.
第二个好处是持久性。
It provides a way to persist the state of our graph,
它提供了一种持久保存图状态的方法，
which enables both memory and human loop, which we're going to see.
这使得内存和人工循环都成为可能，我们将会看到。
And it provides an easy on-ramp for testing debugging and deploying applications.
它为测试、调试和部署应用程序提供了一个简单的入门途径。
Now let's talk about control first.
现在我们先谈谈控制。
Land graph lets you define your applications a graph,
LangGraph能让你把应用定义成图，
with three important things that you just specify.
你只需指定三件重要的事。
The state or the information you want to track over the course of the application,
状态，也就是你想在应用中追踪的信息，
nodes, how do you want to update the state over the course of the application,
节点，你希望如何在应用中更新状态，
and edges, how do you want to connect the nodes together.
以及边，你希望如何连接这些节点。
Now we use the state graph class to initialize a line graph graph,
现在我们用状态图类初始化一个线图，
and we just pass in a state object.
然后传入一个状态对象。
Now the state object is basically the schema for the information we want to track over the course of the application.
状态对象基本上就是我们想在应用中跟踪的信息的模式。
Now there's a few options for defining your schema.
定义模式有几种选择。
As an example, type dicts are fast,
举个例子，类型字典很快，
but they don't support default values.
但它们不支持默认值。
Data classes are actually quite nice because they do support defaults.
数据类其实很好用，因为它们支持默认值。
Padantic is a bit slower, but allows for type validation.
Pydantic 会慢一点，但支持类型验证。
So you can choose the schema that's appropriate for your application.
所以你可以选择适合你应用的模式。
In this simple case, let's just use the type dict.
这个简单例子，我们用类型字典就好。
You can see I'm defining my state schema here.
大家可以看到，我在这里定义了状态模式。
It just has two keys, request, and email both strings.
它只有两个键，请求和电子邮件，都是字符串。
I then initialize my state graph with my schema.
然后我用模式初始化我的状态图。
Now let's take what we did previously.
现在让我们看看之前做的。
We call our model of tools with an input request.
我们用输入请求调用工具模型。
We get the arguments, and we call it tool.
我们获取参数，然后称之为工具。
We can put that all in a node in our graph,
我们可以把它放到图中的一个节点里，
and you'll see two interesting things about this.
你会发现它有两点很有趣。
One, the node takes in our state object.
第一，这个节点接收我们的状态对象。
Remember, we define that above a natural sedictionary.
记住，我们之前把它定义为一个自然字典。
From the dictionary, we can extract any keys we want and utilize them.
我们可以从字典中提取任何键值并使用。
Now the second thing is, it returns a dict.
第二点是，它会返回一个字典。
This return is basically updating our state.
这个返回基本上是在更新我们的状态。
Now by default, when we return from a node,
默认情况下，当我们从一个节点返回时，
it overwrites that particular key in our state,
它会覆盖我们状态中的特定键值，
but when we define our state object,
但当我们定义状态对象时，
there are ways to customize it to do different things,
有些方法可以自定义它，让它做不同的事情，
like appending, and we'll talk about that shortly.
比如追加，我们稍后会讲到。
In this simple case, though, we're going to call our model of tools.
不过，在这个简单的例子中，我们将把工具模型称为
It's going to produce a tool call.
它会生成一个工具调用。
We then pass those arguments to our right email tool.
然后我们把这些参数传给邮件工具。
We can email out, and we'll update or overwrite our state key email with that output.
我们可以发送邮件，然后用输出内容更新或覆盖状态键。
Now we can specify the control flow by adding nodes and edges to our graph.
现在，我们可以通过向图中添加节点和边来指定控制流。
We'll add our single node, right email node,
我们将添加单个节点，即邮件节点，
and two edges to start, go to that node,
并从两个边开始，转到该节点，
from that node, go to end, and finally, we compile it.
从那个节点开始，一直到结束，最后我们编译它。
When we've done these things, we can very easily then run our graph
完成这些后，我们就能很轻松地运行图表了
just by calling invoke, and we can pass an initial value to our state.
只需调用invoke，就能给状态传入初始值。
In this case, we'll initialize our graph with request,
这里，我们用请求初始化图表，
and we see the output of the tool call is written to email in our state.
然后我们看到工具调用的输出被写入了状态中的邮件。
The state dict is just returned.
状态字典已返回。
We run our graph.
我们运行图。
Now in the above case, we very simply used edges to start,
在上面这个例子中，我们简单地用边来开始，
go to our single node, and then go from our single node to end.
到达我们的单节点，然后从单节点到结束。
We can also do conditional routing using conditional edges.
我们也可以使用条件边进行条件路由。
Let me show an example of that.
我来举个例子。
Now let's split our graph up into two different nodes, call the LLM,
现在我们把图分成两个节点，调用大型语言模型，
and run our tool.
然后运行工具。
Now we can add a conditional edge.
现在我们可以添加一个条件边。
It looks to see if a tool call was made by call alone,
它会查看是否通过单独调用进行了工具调用，
and if so, run the tool if not to send.
如果是，就运行工具，否则不发送。
This is a very common thing that we do when we build agents.
这是我们构建智能体时很常见的一种做法。
We use conditional routing as a termination condition.
我们使用条件路由作为终止条件。
If the agent is making a tool call, we run it.
如果智能体正在调用工具，我们就运行它。
If not, we end and exit the agent loop.
如果没有，我们就结束并退出智能体循环。
This is a very useful thing to be aware of.
这点很值得注意。
Now let's see something else that's interesting.
接下来看些有趣的东西。
This time, I initialize my graph with messages state.
这次，我用消息状态初始化图表。
This is a prebuilt state object in line graph.
这是图表里预设的状态对象。
That is a single key messages.
也就是一个关键信息。
And when we update it, as you see here,
当我们更新它时，如你所见，
it just simply depends to that list of messages
它只是简单地附加到消息列表，
as opposed to overwriting.
而不是覆盖。
Now this is also very useful when you're building agents
这在你构建代理时也非常有用，
because you want to basically accumulate messages
因为你希望累积消息。
over the course of the agent's tool calling trajectory.
在智能体的工具调用轨迹中。
And you'll see in this should continue edge.
你们会看到，在“应继续”这个边缘，
All we do is we get the last message
我们所做的就是获取消息列表中的
from the list of messages.
最后一条消息。
We check if it's a tool call.
我们检查它是否是工具调用。
And if so, we return the name of the next node to go to run tool.
如果是，我们就返回下一个要运行的节点的名称。
Otherwise, we end.
否则，就结束。
So you'll see an interesting difference.
你们会看到一个有趣的差异。
With conditional edges,
对于条件边，
you return the name of the next node you want to visit.
你要返回下一个你想访问的节点的名称。
But with nodes,
但对于节点，
you return updates to your state.
你可以更新你的状态。
So we'll compile this and show the graph.
我们来编译一下，展示图表。
So now we start, we call our model.
现在我们开始，调用模型。
And depending upon whether the model likes a tool call,
然后根据模型是否喜欢工具调用，
we'll run the tool or not.
我们会运行工具与否。
Let's go ahead and try that out.
我们来试试看。
And there we go.
成功了。
We pass our input message.
我们传入输入信息。
Our model makes a tool call.
模型调用工具。
We then route to the run tool node.
然后我们连接到运行工具节点。
And the tool is run as we see here.
工具就会像这样运行。
Now with just these local components,
仅用这些本地组件，
you can build a lot of different things.
就能构建出许多不同的东西。
Now because agents are so common,
因为代理很常见，
we have a pre-built abstraction for it,
我们为此预设了一个抽象层，
which I show right here called create react agent.
也就是我在这里展示的“创建React代理”。
Now to this, agent abstraction,
现在，对于这个代理抽象层，
we just pass our model, our list of tools,
我们只需传入模型、工具列表，
and a system prompt.
以及一个系统提示。
We run the agent just like before,
我们像之前一样运行代理，
passing in messages.
传入消息。
And we can see that the model in this case makes a tool call.
我们可以看到模型在这种情况下调用了工具。
The tool is run.
工具开始运行。
Now here's the little difference
现在，这里有个小区别
relative that we saw before.
我们之前看到的亲戚。
Remember before after tools run we just end.
记得吗，之前工具运行后我们直接结束了。
With the agent though as discussed,
但对于代理，正如我们讨论的，
tool calls are returned back to the LLM.
工具调用会返回给大型语言模型。
So what happens is,
所以发生的情况是，
the model then sees that tool call
模型会看到这个工具调用
and provides us a response indicating the tools called
然后给我们一个响应，指出调用的工具
and does not call any further tools.
并且不再调用任何其他工具。
That then exits the tool calling loop
这样就退出了工具调用循环
and the agent ends.
智能体也就结束了。
So now we've seen the basic components of LLM graph.
我们已经了解了LLM图的基本组成部分。
And we've introduced the agent abstraction to LLM graph.
也将代理抽象引入了LLM图。
Now in a very important thing when building agents
构建代理和工作流时，
and workflows, as we're going to see a lot more later,
有一个非常重要的概念，我们稍后会详细介绍，
is the idea of persistence.
那就是持久性。
It can be very useful to allow agents
让智能体在执行
to pause during long-running tasks.
耗时任务时暂停，会非常有用。
Minecraft has a built-in persistence layer
Minecraft 有内置的持久层
to enable this, implemented through check pointers.
可以实现这个功能，通过检查点实现。
Now what happens is, after every node,
现在，每经过一个节点，
the check pointer saves the state of the graph.
检查点会保存图的状态。
So if you pause your graph,
所以如果你暂停图，
the state is saved and available
它的状态就会被保存下来，
for resuming in a later point in time.
方便之后恢复。
Now let's show an example of this.
现在我们来看一个例子。
I can take that same create react agent abstraction
我可以用同样的“create react agent”抽象
and pass it a check pointer.
然后给它一个检查点。
I'll ask something about good practices
我会问一些关于写邮件的好习惯。
for writing emails.
写邮件的好习惯。
Now with a check pointer,
现在有了检查点，
you'll see I need to now pass a thread ID.
你会看到我需要传入一个线程ID。
This basically groups checkpoints together
这基本上把检查点归类到一起，
so I can reference them later.
这样我以后可以引用它们。
Our agent ran.
我们的代理运行了。
And what's really nice is,
真正好的是，
we can get this current state of our agent
我们可以获取智能体的当前状态
just by passing in the thread.
只要传入线程。
We'll call agent.getState.
我们会调用agent.getState。
And we can go ahead and extract
然后我们可以提取
all the messages currently in state of our agent.
智能体当前状态中的所有消息。
Now currently we see we just have our input
现在我们看到，我们只有输入
and we have the agent's response.
和智能体的回复。
Now let's continue the conversation.
现在我们继续对话。
All I need to do is re-invoke my agent
我只需要重新调用我的智能体
and I'll say, hey great,
然后我会说，太棒了，
let's use lesson three,
我们用第三课
be concise to craft a response to my boss
简洁地回复老板
and I can just pass in the config.
我可以直接传入配置
That config indicates the thread.
该配置表示线程
If I can run, we can see the agent then
如果我能运行，我们就能看到代理
has access to the prior messages
它可以访问之前的消息
because they're saved to the thread
因为它们都保存在对话串里
and it proposes an email.
然后它会生成一封邮件。
I can then follow up again
我就可以继续操作
by passing in that thread ID
传入那个对话串ID
and say I like this.
然后说我喜欢这个。
Go ahead and write the email.
你去写这封邮件。
And now you can see it goes ahead,
现在你可以看到它会
calls the tool.
调用工具。
The tool is executed
工具已执行
and it confirms that the email has been sent.
确认邮件已发送。
Now another very powerful thing
另外一个非常强大的功能
that check pointing allows
是检查点允许
is that we can interrupt our graph
我们中断图表
at very specific points.
在非常特定的点。
Here's an example of a very simple graph
这是一个非常简单的图表示例
where I want to interrupt
我想在这里中断
at a particular node human feedback
在特定节点处进行人工反馈
to collect feedback from the user.
以收集用户的反馈。
All you do is add this interrupt object
你只需添加这个中断对象
to the node
到节点
and compile my graph with a checkpointer.
用检查点编译图表。
We can see our graph flow here.
我们能看到图表流程。
We'll create a thread like before.
我们会像之前一样创建线程。
We'll run a graph.
我们会运行图表。
Now I'll just simply stream updates
现在我只需简单地
to each node as the graph is running
将更新流式传输到每个节点
by indicating the stream mode updates.
通过指示流模式更新。
Now it's interesting here
有趣的是
when we hit that human feedback node,
当我们触及人工反馈节点时，
we can see the graph emits an interrupt.
图表发出中断
With a value, please provide feedback
请给出反馈值
and that's exactly what we passed to
这正是我们传给
that interrupt object.
中断对象的参数
Now to resume,
现在，要恢复
all you need to do is use this command object
你只需使用这个命令对象
in the line graph
在折线图中
and pass in whatever human feedback I want.
传入我想要的任何人工反馈。
Now to resume from the interrupt,
现在要从中断中恢复，
we just invoke our graph again
我们只需再次调用图表
with the command object
用命令对象
and we pass resume.
然后传入resume
We can simply pass a string
我们直接传入字符串
and our feedback gets passed through
我们的反馈会传递给
to our node
我们的节点
and written to our state
并写入到我们的状态中
as user feedback.
作为用户反馈。
So whatever we pass
所以我们传递的任何内容
to this resume
到这个简历中
and command after an interrupt
并在中断后发出命令
is directly passed into our graph.
直接传入我们的图表。
And what we can see right here
我们现在能看到的是
is where we received that feedback,
我们收到反馈的地方，
run it to state.
将其运行到某个状态。
Now because I set these two environment variables,
因为我设置了这两个环境变量，
everything we just did
我们刚才做的一切
is logged to Langsmith.
都记录在Langsmith里了。
I can then look at my Langsmith traces
我可以查看Langsmith的追踪记录
for any of the above executions.
看看上面任何一次执行。
Here's an example looking at our agent
这是一个查看我们代理的例子
and we see here in Langsmith.
我们在Langsmith里看到
Here are graph nodes for our agent.
这是我们代理的图节点。
We can open this up.
我们可以打开它。
This shows us the model call specifically.
这具体展示了模型调用。
Open that up.
打开它。
And you can see here are the bound tools.
你可以看到，这是绑定工具。
We actually called the right email tool right here.
我们称之为“右键邮件工具”。
Here is a list of messages,
这里是消息列表，
the L and received.
已发送和已接收的。
And then here is the resulting tool call.
然后是工具调用的结果。
We then went to the tool node,
然后我们来到工具节点，
open that up,
打开它，
and you can see here is the tool in vocation
你会看到这是工具的调用
and the output of our tool
以及我们工具的输出
as a tool message.
作为一条工具消息。
And finally, that went back to our agent.
最后，它回到了我们的代理。
We can see that call model,
我们可以看到那个调用模型，
node,
节点，
we can look at the L and call specifically,
我们可以专门看看L和调用，
see that node tools called
看看那个节点工具调用
and a module response
模块会响应
with an IAM message saying
一条IAM消息
that email has been sent.
说邮件已发送。
So Langsmith is very nice way to dig into your traces
Langsmith能很好地帮你追踪
and it also logs useful metadata for you
还能记录有用的元数据
as you can see over here.
大家可以看到
Now in addition to Langsmith,
除了Langsmith
I want to talk about another important
我还想谈谈另一个
and useful feature in the Langtrain ecosystem
Langchain生态系统中的重要功能
that allows us to deploy agents
它可以部署智能体
or workflows very easily.
或工作流。
And that's called Langarth platform.
这就是Langarth平台。
So everything we've done here in a notebook
我们在笔记本里做的一切
is great for testing
都很适合测试
and for rapid prototyping.
和快速原型开发。
But what if I want to turn any of this code
但如果我想把这些代码
into a deployable application?
变成可部署的应用呢？
That's where Langarth platform comes in.
这就是Langarth平台的作用。
It makes it very easy to go
它让这一切变得非常容易，
from workflow agents to
从工作流代理到
a deployable server
一个可部署的服务器
with an API that we can use to interact with our graph.
通过API与图数据交互。
In addition,
此外，
Langarth platform gives us
Langarth平台还提供
an interactive IDE called Langarth Studio.
一个交互式IDE，叫Langarth Studio。
It's a very useful way to further inspect
这是一个非常有用的方法，可以进一步检查
and debug our agent.
和调试我们的代理。
So to use Langarth platform,
要使用Langsmith平台，
all we need to do is ensure that our project
我们需要做的就是确保我们的项目
has a structure as shown here.
具有如图所示的结构。
So the thing that really matters here
最重要的是
is this Langarth.json.
这个Langarth.json文件。
This is just a configuration file.
它只是一个配置文件。
In the root of this repo,
在这个仓库的根目录里，
this just specifies dependencies, graphs,
它只指定了依赖项、图表，
environment variables,
环境变量，
and other things needed to start
以及启动
the Langarth server.
Langarth服务器所需的其他东西。
It's a pretty simple configuration.
这是一个相当简单的配置。
The main thing the configuration will have
配置主要包含
is just simply the graph names
只是图表名称
and the path.
和路径。
As an example,
举个例子，
in a repo,
在一个仓库里，
in this directory,
在这个目录下，
we have a file called Langarth 101.py,
我们有个文件叫Langarth 101.py，
which contains some of the code
里面包含一些代码
that we just prototyped in this notebook
是我们刚在这个笔记本里
as a deployable graph.
作为可部署图表原型化的。
Now with Langarth platform,
现在有了Langarth平台，
there's a few different deployment options.
有几种不同的部署方式。
I want to make sure our clear.
我想确保我们讲清楚。
So the simplest and free option is just local deployment
最简单、免费的方式是本地部署，
that runs on your local machine,
它在你的本地机器上运行，
and all I need to do from the root of this directory
我只需要在这个目录的根目录下
is run Langarth dev.
是运行Langarth开发版。
Now this still has persistence,
它现在仍有持久性，
checkpoints should be written to the local file system.
检查点应该写入本地文件系统。
Now they're also very self-hosted options for deployment,
也有很多自托管部署选项，
and there's hosted deployments,
还有托管部署，
which use Postgres,
使用Postgres
for persistence.
进行持久化。
So we'll just run Langarth dev
所以我们直接在
from the root of our repo,
仓库根目录运行Langarth dev，
and see what happens.
看看会发生什么。
So if we run Langarth dev,
运行Langarth dev后，
you'll see this spin up in your browser.
浏览器会弹出这个界面。
This is Langarth Studio.
这是Langarth Studio。
You can scroll through the various graphs
你可以浏览各种图表，
that are existence repo.
它们都存在于repo中。
Click on Langarth 101.
点击“朗加斯101”。
This is one of the graphs we built in the notebook.
这是我们在笔记本中构建的图表之一。
We can open up this input pane,
我们可以打开这个输入窗格，
open up messages,
打开消息，
pass in a message,
传入一条消息，
submit,
提交，
and you can see the state of the graph
就能看到图的状态
over here,
在这里，
which shows each node in the graph,
它显示了图中的每个节点，
as well as the state updates,
以及状态更新，
at that particular node.
在那个特定节点。
You can also click on this open-run Langsmiths,
你也可以点击“打开运行Langsmiths”，
and look at the trace to see the LM call,
查看轨迹，了解语言模型调用，
in the call LM node,
在调用语言模型节点中，
as well as the tool execution in the run tool node.
以及在运行工具节点中的工具执行。
Now another nice thing I'll point out
另外，我还想指出一点
is that you can see the API docs for your local deployment,
你可以在这里看到本地部署的API文档，
right here,
就在这儿，
and you can browse through
你可以浏览一下
to see all the endpoints available to you.
看看所有可用的端点。
So we've covered many of the foundations needed
我们已经讲了这门课的很多基础知识
for this course.
了。
We've covered Langchain
我们讲了Langchain
in some of the useful interfaces,
和一些有用的接口，
such as init chat model,
比如init chat model，
tools,
工具，
and using chat models.
以及聊天模型。
We've talked about the basis of Langarth
我们讨论了LangChain的基础
and agents versus workflows.
以及代理和工作流的区别。
We also showed both Langsmith,
我们还展示了LangSmith，
as well as Langarth deployment
以及Langarth部署
and Langarth Studio.
和Langarth Studio。
We covered persistence and interrupts.
我们讲了持久性和中断。
We also covered Langsmith and observability,
我们还讲了Langsmith和可观测性，
as well as Langarth platform,
以及Langarth平台，
showcasing local deployments,
展示本地部署，
and Langarth Studio.
以及Langarth Studio。
So these are really all the foundations
这些都是你接下来课程中
you're going to need for the rest of this course.
需要用到的所有基础知识。